This is the grave I've chosen for Shilang
这是我为石狼挑选的坟墓
This place is called Tiannan Pass
此处名为天南关
Composed of two peaks, east and west
由东西两座山峰组成
Adjacent to Tianhe
毗邻巅河
Only one narrow path in between for troops to pass
中间只有一条小道可以通过行军
If a large army marches here
大军若行至此处
They will inevitably form a long line
必然排成长列
Front and rear cannot support each other
首尾难以相顾
We only need
我们只需
To lure the enemy here
诱敌行至此处
The vanguard
由前军
Will block Shilang
堵住石狼
The rear guard will take the mountain paths
后军则从山谷间的小路
In groups to encircle from behind
分批绕后
If we encounter enemy troops
如果遇到敌军
Don't engage
不要纠缠
Just disperse them
只需驱散
And I
而我
Will set the central camp on the mountain
会将中军大营设在山上
After Shilang's main force is attacked
石狼主力遇到袭击之后
They will surely flee along the mountain paths
定会从山谷间的小路逃散
At that time
届时
I will personally lead the central army to intercept the fleeing enemy
我会亲率中军截杀敌人逃兵
This battle
此战
Must completely annihilate their 50,000 main force
务必要将他们的五万主力军
Completely
全数歼灭
In this way
如此一来
Shi Wei's so-called 180,000 army
石魏所谓的十八万大军
Will scatter like birds and beasts
也将化作鸟兽散
The Central Plains can be pacified
中原可定
The task of luring the enemy is very dangerous
诱敌任务十分凶险
Who is willing to be the vanguard?
谁愿为先锋
Father
父皇
You can't catch a wolf without risking the child
舍不得孩子 套不着狼
Your son is willing to be the vanguard
儿臣愿为先锋
Good
好
I'll give you a unit of elite cavalry
我给你一队精骑
To lure Shilang's main force into the pass
引石狼主力入关
Yes
是
Halt
站住
Who goes there?
什么人
They say Wuzhao people are brave and skilled
都说邬伖人骁勇善战
How
怎么
How come all I see today are cowards?
怎么今天爷爷我见到的都是缩头王八呀
Everyone inside, listen
里面都给我听着
Who dares come out and fight me?
谁敢出来跟爷爷一战
Young General
少将军
General Shilang said
石狼将军说了
No one is to go out and fight
谁都不能出城迎战呐
To hell with that
去他奶奶的
I'll kill this brat first
老子先宰了这小兔崽子再说
Young General
少将军
Report
报
Shilang's army is moving
石狼大军动了
Good, the Second Prince is brave
好啊 是二皇子威武啊
If Shilang wants to maintain morale
他石狼若想保住士气
He will surely follow
就势必会跟进
Zu Yue
祖月
Lead your troops
你率所部兵马
To face the Second Prince head-on
正面迎接老二
Fight while retreating
边战边退
Your servant
臣
Receives the order
领命
Zhu Yuanzhi
朱元之
Half an hour after Shilang's main force enters the pass
待石狼主力入关后半个时辰
Lead the ambush troops to attack
你率伏兵出击
Block Shilang's army's retreat
堵住石狼大军后路
Your servant receives the order
臣 领命
Brat, give me back my son's life
小子 还我儿命来
Bad, there's an ambush
不好 有埋伏
Kill
杀
Kill them
给我杀
Report
报
Shilang's army has all entered the pass
石狼大军已全部进入隘口
Shilang discovered he's surrounded
石狼发现被围
Instead of retreating, he advances
不退反进
Sending heavy armor to break through
派重甲军凿阵
One charge has broken through two lines
一轮冲锋已经突破两道封锁
They know they're ambushed
他们明知中伏
Yet still lead the army deeper
却还率军深入
Report
报
Minister Li Dingyuan
李定远李大人
Sent an urgent message from the rear
快马送来后方急信
Your Majesty
陛下
Some are planning rebellion
有人思变
Minister Li says
李大人说
Many gentry believe this battle is hopeless
不少士族都觉得此战无望
And are stirring panic in the rear
在后方煽动恐慌
The Chen and Xie families
陈家和谢家
Will handle it
会处理好的
Your Majesty
陛下
But the Chen family head
可陈家的家主
Is now the Second Prince's mother
现在是二皇子的母妃啊